writingclasses.com 2018-12-22

# Privacy Policy - Gotham Writers Workshop

## What information do we collect?

### We collect some information directly ****

We collect information from you when you register on our site, place an order, subscribe to our mailing list, or respond to a survey. 

When ordering or registering on our site, you may be asked to enter your name, email address, street address, phone number, or credit card information. 

### We collect some information automatically 

Our website uses cookies to help us compile data about site traffic and to ensure the proper functioning of our shopping cart. Our site will recognize information like your IP address, what type of devices are used, high-level location information (e.g., city or state), and user behavior (such as how long users stay on the website and which links users click on). This information is only used in aggregate and is not used for any purpose except to ensure the proper functioning and security of the web site. 

## What do we use your information for?

Any of the information we collect from you may be used in one of the following ways: 

  * To personalize your experience  
(Your information helps us to better respond to your individual needs.) 

  * To improve our website  
(We continually strive to improve our website offerings based on the information and feedback we receive from you.) 

  * To improve customer service  
(Your information helps us to more effectively respond to your customer service requests and support needs.) 

  * To process transactions  
(Your information, whether public or private, will not be sold, exchanged, transferred, or given to any other company for any reason whatsoever, without your consent, other than for the express purpose of delivering the purchased product or service requested.) 

  * To send periodic emails with your consent  
(The email address you provide for order processing, may be used to send you information and updates pertaining to your order. If you chose to be added to the email list, we will send you information pertaining to writing advice, news, and special deals. If at any time you would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, we include detailed unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each email.) 

## How do we protect your information?

We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information when you place an order or enter, submit, or access your personal information. 

We offer the use of a secure server. All supplied sensitive/credit information is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology and then encrypted into our Payment gateway providers database only to be accessible by those authorized with special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the information confidential. 

After the payment transaction is complete, we save only the last four digits of your credit card number in our company database. The rest of the number is not saved in our system. 

## Do we use cookies?

Yes. We use cookies to help us remember and process the items in your shopping cart, understand and save your preferences for future visits, and compile aggregate data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools in the future. 

(Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser—if you allow—that enables the sites or service provider's systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information) 

**Our web site uses these cookies:**

  * Session ID: so our shopping cart works properly in a single web session (expires as soon as you close your browser window).
  * Order Number: so we’ll remember what’s in your cart if you leave our site and come back later. No personal data is stored in this cookie, and the number is encrypted (expires after two weeks).
  * User identifier: so we can differentiate you from other users. No personal data is stored in this cookie, and the number is encrypted (expires after two weeks if you clicked “remember me” when you logged in; otherwise, it expires when you close your browser window).
  * ReferringUrl: so we can bookmark the page you were on and take you back there when you are finished completing a task—for instance, after a password reset (expires when you close your browser window).
  * CSRF: a cookie that helps to protect our site from malicious activity. It’s a random number and has no personal relation to you (expires when you close your browser window).

 **Third-Party cookies:  
** Our web site sets several types of third-party cookies used for marketing research. Third party cookies may include:

  * Google Analytics: we use Google Analytics to collect data about website usage. This data does not include personally identifiable information. You can view the Google Privacy Policy here: www.google.com/policies/privacy/.
  * Google and Facebook Remarketing (non-EU/EEA users only): because you have visited our site, you may see our ads on Google’s Display Advertising Network of partner websites, on Google’s own search results pages, or on Facebook. If you have a Google account, you can opt out of Google remarketing, by setting your Google Ad Settings. To opt out of Facebook remarketing, see Your Ad Preferences, and disallow “Ads based on data from partners”.
  * BingAds: we use BingAds Universal Event Tracking to collect website usage data on traffic from the Bing Search Engine. No personally identifiable information is sent to Microsoft. 
  * NewRelic and Cloudflare: we use these companies to monitor and ensure the smooth operation and security of our web site. They place cookies to differentiate users, but no personal information is stored in those cookies.

## Do we disclose any information to outside parties?

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. This does not include trusted third parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential and only as necessary to complete services for Gotham Writers Workshop. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others' rights, property, or safety. However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses. 

## Third party links

Occasionally, at our discretion, we may include or offer third party products or services on our website. These third party sites have separate and independent privacy policies. We therefore have no responsibility or liability for the content and activities of these linked sites. Nonetheless, we seek to protect the integrity of our site and welcome any feedback about these sites. 

## Changing your information

Current and former students may update their personal information in the [Gotham Student Center](https://gothamwriters.com/student). Email list members may change their information by clicking the "Settings" link at the bottom of any of our emails. And anyone may change his or her information by calling Gotham Writers Workshop at 212-974-8377. 

## California Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance

We are in compliance with the California Online Privacy Protection Act (OPPA). We therefore will not distribute your personal information to outside parties without your consent. 

## Children's Online Privacy Protection Act Compliance

We are in compliance with the requirements of COPPA (Children's Online Privacy Protection Act). We do not collect any information from anyone under 13 years of age. Our website, products, and services are all directed to people who are at least 13-years-old. 

## Your Consent

By using our site, you consent to our privacy policy. 

## Changes to our Privacy Policy

This version of the policy has been in effect since December 3, 2014. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page. 

## Contacting Us

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy you may contact us here: 

Gotham Writers Workshop   
555 Eighth Avenue, #1402   
New York, NY 10018   
USA 

[[email protected]  
](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#2f4c40415b4e4c5b6f48405b474e42585d465b4a5d5c014c4042)[www.gothamwriters.com](http://www.gothamwriters.com/)
